#### Contact

www.linkedin.com/in/rohanshashank-260b6776 (LinkedIn) careers.microsoft.com/us/en (Company)

### Top Skills

Human Resources
Recruiting
Benefits Negotiation

## Languages

English (Full Professional) Hindi (Native or Bilingual)

#### Certifications

Tech Recruitment Certified Professional

People Analytics and Evidence-Based Management

Tech Recruiter Certification

Recruiter Training - Hire Top Employees in 30 days

# Rohan Shashank

Recruiter at Microsoft

Bengaluru

# Summary

Highly motivated full-cycle recruiter. Experience in Banking, E-Commerce, Insurance and Retail industries. I've established a reputation for streamlining the hiring process by efficiently and effectively working within an organization to achieve strategic growth. Created Daily and weekly reports using MS Office. My methods of recruiting were to network through LinkedIn, personal database, Dice, Monster, Indeed, Naukri.com, ATS, GitHub, referrals and standard recruiting techniques. Knowledge of market/talent mapping using LinkedIn, Glassdoor, Crunchbase and Owler. Strong human resources professional with a Bachelor of Technology (B.Tech) focused in Computer Engineering.

# Experience

Microsoft

Recruiter

November 2019 - Present (10 months)

Bengaluru Area, India

### Wipro Limited

Sr. Talent Acquisition Specialist May 2019 - November 2019 (7 months)

Bengaluru Area, India

#### Responsibilities:

- Interact with stakeholders to understand hiring requirements, develop sourcing strategies and attending weekly meetings.
- Creating job description and posting on various job boards like LinkedIn,
   Naukri along with Employee Referral Programs.
- Utilizing and maintain all statistical data in applicant tracking system associated with the recruitment of open positions ensuring timely and accurate information processing.
- Manage all phases of full cycle recruiting, from initial sourcing and screening through offer negotiations, placement and on-boarding.

- Identified more than 100 candidates for SFDC during 3 months of tenure with 95% joining ratio with 55 cycle time (days).
- Leverage social media channels to strategically source talent and create a pipeline.
- Source/screen/qualify and hire top quality candidates. Develop a plentiful pipeline of qualified talent. Anticipate/ prepare for future skill requirements.
- Worked as a SPOC for handling recruitment walk-in drives for multiple skills/ positions in Bangalore as well as other cities.
- Efforts focused on recruiting IT professionals (Salesforce Lightning Developer, Salesforce Commerce Cloud, Salesforce Marketing Cloud).

#### Accolite

#### Recruiter

April 2018 - January 2019 (10 months)

Bengaluru Area, India

#### Responsibilities:

- Interact with stakeholders to understand hiring requirements & develop sourcing strategies.
- Draft job descriptions in consultation with stakeholders create and manage job postings.
- Employ, Boolean searches in LinkedIn, Naukri, Instahyre and internal database to source applicants.
- Monitor/track candidate pipeline to ensure it is adequate to meet the requirements of open vacancies.
- Pre-screen job applicants, coordinate and schedule interviews and provide feedback to candidates & stakeholders.
- Negotiate & extend offers, organize candidate start dates/ orientations and process new joiner information.
- Manage administrative processes including scheduling interviews, facilitating background & reference checks etc.
- Worked as a SPOC for handling recruitment walk-in drives for multiple skills/ positions.
- Reviewed high volumes of resumes, screened, interviewed and made hiring decisions.
- Preparation of daily, weekly and monthly report relating to resume sourcing, interviews happened, Offer Made and Candidates Joined.
- Efforts focused on recruiting IT professionals (.Net Developer, Java Developer, Quality Analyst, Angular Developer)

#### Collabera Inc.

#### **Technical Recruiter**

March 2016 - March 2018 (2 years 1 month)

Bengaluru Area, India

#### Responsibilities:

- Responsible for contract and permanent positions for E-Commerce (majorly Amazon), Retail (Best Buy), Banking and Fortune 500 companies.
- Provide excellent, one-stop recruitment and selection service to current clients, new clients and other clients as assigned as well as for upcoming bids and proposals.
- Handled Vanilla and Niche skill for Mid-Level Executives to Senior-Level Leadership roles for IT/Non-IT requirements.
- Extensively used Boolean searches to extract the exact matching skills required for the given client requirement.
- Sourced candidates for IT and Non-IT segments through diverse channels such as job portals like - Dice, Monster, CB, Indeed, Ladders, Internal ATS and from other networks such as vendor networking, Google search, LinkedIn and through reference.
- Responsible for daily recruitment functions include sourcing potential technical and non-technical candidates, interviewing and salary/compensation negotiations.
- Responsible for skill match, interview applicants regarding work history, education, training, checking references, negotiating terms and rates for each project, coordinating the interview process, extending offers, and closing candidates by completing all paperwork's and background check in accordance with state and federal employment laws.
- Efforts focused on recruiting IT professionals (BI Engineer, Project Manager, Quality Analyst, DevOps, Catalogue Specialist, Data Engineer).

#### **TEKWISSEN LLC**

2 years

Sr.Technical Recruiter August 2014 - June 2015 (11 months)

Bengaluru Area, India

#### Requirement analysis and Talent Sourcing

- Understanding client requirements for various job profiles.
- Sourcing of candidates for IT and Non-IT segments through diverse channels such as job boards, external consultants, references, databases and social networking.
- Educating the consultants about the various job profiles.

Recruitment Process Management

- Performed initial screening of candidates over phone for communication, technical competencies, attitude, behavioral fit and shortlisting candidates based on client requirement.
- Scheduled further rounds of interviews and all follow up action thereafter till closures.
- Managing salary negotiations and offer communications.

#### **Technical Recruiter**

July 2013 - July 2014 (1 year 1 month)

Vishakhapatnam Area, India

- · Having Bench placement experience.
- Supporting the company to place bench candidates for multiple clients.
- Requirement Analysis (understanding of requisition).
- Review and formatting of resumes of bench candidates and negotiate rates.
- Screening and short listing of candidates as per clients requirements.
- Coordinating further rounds of interviews and all follow up action thereafter till closures.
- End-End Recruitment Process.
- Ensure that bench consultants are placed within schedule time.
- Responsible for achieving results that may affect deadlines.
- Follow up the candidates till the joining.
- Contacting candidates and conducting preliminary interviews which include communication skills, current skills and expectations.
- Hands on experience in job Portals like Dice, Tech Fetch, and Carrier Builder, Monster etc.
- Understanding various client requirements.
- Educating the candidate on the job profile.
- Initial screening of profiles based on requirements and assessing their communication, technology, competency, attitude and fitment.

# Education

Hi-Tech College Of Engineering

Bachelor of Technology (B.Tech.), Computer Engineering · (2009 - 2013)